because sets in the set operations like
Union and intersection and complement
are all defined in terms of some logic
condition like or or and or not in it
means that all of those rules of logic
that we got all those logical
equivalences can be applied to the
language of set and therefore we get a
lot of equalities of sets so for example
consider this claim I'm claiming that a
union B equals B Union a so how could we
prove a claim like this again I want you
to notice inequality so I want to show
if it's in the Union a union B then it's
in the B Union a and vice versa
if it's in B Union a then it's an a
union B I want to show both sides of
that so I want to say show that what my
proof is going forward everything is in
biconditional
and if and only if so what I'm going to
use the element method mainly I'm going
to start with an element X which is
inside of the a and the B inside of a
union B but the definition of a union B
and by the way all definitions are
inherently if and only if you don't have
to worry about that if you're applying a
definition it is always if anomia so X
is an a union B is the same thing as X
is in a or I'm going to put this symbol
for my disjunctive or X is inside of B
but now we can use a property that we
had for disjunctive we know that two
properties that are connected with an or
that I can reverse that order that I can
say that this is the same thing as X
inside of B or X is inside of a indeed
back in the day we would have verified
this logical property by looking at it
at level of truth tables this is P or Q
and this is Q or P and you can verify
that they have the same truth table so
this is a logical equivalence and then I
can go backwards X and B or X and a this
is precisely the same thing
saying that X is in B Union a and so I
have a chain of if and only if and I get
if I start in a union B I end up in B
Union a and the key thing to note here
is that the important property is
something about logic the the reversing
the order came down here is a logical
property and then because the Union was
defined in terms of this or statement
you could sort of bring it out of the
logical property into this statement
about unions but the same is true in a
much larger domain for instance we have
a de Morgan's law for logic we have a de
Morgan's law for sets and that idea is
going to continue for all of the
different logical equivalences